Kevin Dawe

Technical Specialist

<u>kevindawe.ca</u> | <u>github.com/kld87</u> | <u>medium.com/@kevindawe</u> <u>kevin.dawe@gmail.com</u> | London, Ontario, CA | Remote

About

Passionate techie and dedicated full-stack developer with 10+ years of experience in the industry. Served as product owner, team leader, and senior developer for SaaS-based web applications. Possesses a broad skill set including programming, sysadmin, devops, IT security, technical writing, and scaling infrastructure for a rapidly growing company.

Currently seeking interesting opportunities in the tech sector in the systems, security, and development space.

Primary Skills

Development: HTML/CSS, PHP (Laravel), JavaScript (React, node.js, AngularJS), Python, Java, MySQL, Postgres, Shell Scripting

DevOps: Atlassian Products, git, grunt, gulp, npm, Vagrant, Docker, composer **Systems:** Linux (Ubuntu) and Windows server administration, network administration (subnetting, VLANs, routing, VPNs, firewalls, IDS/IPS), IT Security, Apache & nginx configuration, VOIP (Avaya)

Other: GIS (PostGIS, OpenLayers, Leaflet, QGIS, Geoserver), technical writing & interviewing

Work Experience

Scalable Path - https://scalablepath.com

Technical Editor & Interviewer

Part-Time, Remote, Oct. 2019 - Present

- Prepared and administered technical assessments for software developers
- Wrote and edited blog posts
- Served as a technical subject matter expert for marketing content
- Wrote and reviewed copy for various public-facing tools and pages
- Participated in regular marketing and recruiting meetings

PSD Research, Consulting, and Software - http://psdrcs.com

Senior Full Stack Developer, Systems Administrator

Full-Time, London ON, 2010 - Aug. 2019

Part-Time, Remote, 2006 - 2010

 Product owner, team leader, and lead developer on various asset management, financial, and geospatial SaaS applications for the Canadian public sector market

- Coded primarily in PHP, PostgreSQL, AngularJS, and Bootstrap
- Developed various scripts and 3rd-party integrations with client systems
- Performed code review, caught SQL injection, CSRF, and directory transversal vulnerabilities before they were added to the code base
- Responsible for sysadmin, including multiple on-prem Ubuntu Linux servers (production and internal), network infrastructure (including remote sites), and an Avaya VOIP system
- Responsible for devops, including administration of self-hosted Atlassian products (JIRA, BitBucket, Bamboo, Confluence) including a build/testing server, data migration, and deployment procedures
- Organized and ran programming and security challenges for the development group
- Assisted HR with interviewing candidates and technical screening

Scotiabank

Security Research Intern Scarborough ON, Sept. 2009 - Apr. 2010

- Researched hardware & software security solutions for potential use within the organization
- Organized and managed a team consisting of four other interns
- Evaluated and tested security claims of potential solutions
- Collaborated with vendors to acquire necessary product information and demonstrations
- Compiled reports and recommendations based on project results that were then presented to upper management

Atec Computer Systems

Web Application Developer

Part-Time, Remote, 2006 - 2008

- Developed web applications primarily based in PHP & MySQL for clients
- Designed and implemented inventory management, electronic document management, and image gallery applications
- Created automated email-based notification systems
- Installed and managed a LAMP server and several associated domains

Education

Ontario Tech University (formerly UOIT)

Bachelor of Information Technology (Honours) Network Security Specialization Oshawa ON, 2006 - 2010

References

Available upon request